ILGWU Memorabilia 5780 MB
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Memorabilia
1965-2002
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
5780 MB
35.33 cubic feet
35.3 linear ft.
Memorabilia, memorabilia.
This collection consists of various collectibles from the ILGWU, such as badges, buttons, ball-point pens, tie tacks, money clips, newspaper articles, plaques, photos, scarf, t-shirt, books, banners and more.
5915877
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 21, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 26, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of various collectibles from the ILGWU, such as badges, buttons, ball-point pens, tie tacks, money clips, newspaper articles, plaques, photos, scarf, t-shirt, books, banners and more.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/002: ILGWU David Dubinsky Correspondence
Labor unions--Collectibles.; Barroff, Abraham.; Clinton, Bill, 1946-; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982; Gore, Al, 1948-; Sofo, Arturo.; AFL-CIO --Archives.; AFL-CIO --Collectibles.; American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers' Association --Archives.; Apparel Job Training and Research Corporation --Archives.; Brotherhood of Christians and Jews --Archives.; Gewerkschaft Textil-Bekleidung --Archives.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union --Archives.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union --Collectibles.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 1 (New York, N.Y.)--Archives.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 116 (Fort Wayne, Ind.)--Archives.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 48 (New York, N.Y.)--Archives.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 9 (New York, N.Y.)--Archives.; Italian Cloak, Suit, Skirt & Reefer Makers' Union (New York, N.Y.) --Archives.; Justice --Archives.; Knights of Columbus --Archives.; Military Order of Cootie - -Archives.; New Jersey State Federation of Labor --Archives.; New York State Federation of Labor --Archives.; United Jewish Appeal --Archives.; American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers' Associaiton--Archives; Brotherhood of Christians and Jews--Archives; Apparel Job Training and Research Corporation--Archives
5915877
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union - Badges, 1983; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Badges with pendants - 'Honor Guest' (yellow); 'Vice President' (green); 'Delegate' (blue); 'Genl. Sec-Treas' (white); 'President' (white); 'Exec. Vice Pres' (red); 'Press' (orange); 'Sgt At Arms' (red/white/blue); 'Staff' (white); Pendants have writing "Thirty-Eighth Convention, Hollywood, Fla., May 27, 1983"
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union - Badges (Dupl), 1983; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 2)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union - Badges (Dupl), 1983; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 3)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union - Badges, buttons, push-pins, sewing kits, pens, 1910; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Buttons - "Clinton/Gore - It's time for a change!"; push-pins - "ILGWU"; buttons - "ILGWU, AFL-CIO"; badges - "Cloak & Skirt Trade Madison Sq., June 29th, 1910"; "Skirt Makers"; sewing kits (samples of thread, needles)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union - Badges, 1971-1983; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Badges - ILGWU - "Guest" for 34th, & 38th Conventions; "Vice President" for 38th; "Delegate" for 36th; "Genl. Sec-Treas" for 38th
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union - Badges, 1944-1980; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Badges - ILGWU - "Delegate" for 25th (Boston, Mass. 1944), 29th (Atlantic City 1956), 34th (Miami Beach 1971), 35th (Miami Beach 1974), 37th (New York 1980); "Guest" for 32nd (Miami 1965), 34th (Miami 1971), 35th (Miami 1974), 37th (New York 1980); "First Vice Pres." & "Gen. Secy. Treas." for 33rd (Atlantic City 1968)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union & AFL-CIO - Badges, 1952-1983; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Badges - ILGWU - "Delegate" for 34th (Miami Beach 1971), 37th (New York 1980; "Guest" for 35th (Miami 1974), 37th (New York 1980), AFL-CIO - "Guest" for 5th biennial (New York 1963), 71st (New York 1962), 15th biennial (Hollywood, Fla 1963), 4th biennial (Miami 1961)
- Badges for N.J. State Federation of Labor, Military Order of Cootie, ILGWU, 1940-1961; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Badges - "N.J. State Federation of Labor" (Newark, N.J. 1961 & Atlantic City, N.J. 1954); "Military Order of Cootie"; "Int. Ladies Garment Workers Union, Union Made, ILGWU"; "I.L.G.W.U. 28th Convention"; "Delegate pin with British and America flags, and Eagle; pendant from a badge for "ILGWU" in the shape of a thread spool, dated 1940.
- Buttons and badges - miscellaneous, 1948-1984; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Buttons - "Israel Histadrut, National Convention1950"; "New York Convention Center, 1984"; "International Ladies' Garbment Workers' Union, 38th Convention1983"; badges - "Guest" of 90th Annual Convention, New York State Federation of Labor1953"; "Delegate" for 8th Annual Convention, New York1946"; "Delegate" for N.J. State Federation of Labor1954"
- ILGWU - buttons, Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Buttons - "ILGWU, AFL-CIO, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Organized 1900"
- ILGWU - buttons, Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Buttons - "Contratto 88"; "Contract 88"; "Local 23-25 ILGWU"; "Local 23-25, Committee to Defend the Union Contract, ILGWU", "Local 23-25, ILGWU, Shop Representative"; "Save Our Jobs, ILGWU, Veto the Veto"
- ILGWU - buttons, Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Buttons - "Solidarity, American Movement"; "Keep New York a Union Town"; "Liberty & Union, ILGWU"; "I Am An Active Retiree, "International Ladies'"; "Created with Pride in U.S.A."; "Forward with Lewis and CIO"; "10th Anniversary. Antiguq Workers Union"; "ILGWU, Women's Health Brigade, 1942"; "Union Defenders Committee..."; "Look for our Label... We'll Look for Yours!"
- ILGWU - badges, 1956-1965; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Badges - "Press", "Honor Guest" for 29th Convention (Atlantic City); "Sergeant. At Arms", "Honor Guest", "Delegate" for 30th Convention (Miami Beach); "Delegate" for 31st Convention (Atlantic City); "Delegate", "Staff", "Guest", "Delegate" for 32nd Convention (Miami Beach) of the ILGWU, AFL-CIO.
- ILGWU - badges, 1968-1983; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Badges - "Guest", "President" for 33rd Convention (Atlantic City); "Guest", "Executive Pres.", "Delegate" for the 36th Convention (Hollywood, Fla.); "Guest" for 37th Convention (New York); "Exec. Vice Pres.", "Guest" for 38th Convention (Hollywood, Fla) of the ILGWU, AFL-CIO, CLC.
- ILGWU - badges, 1937-1944; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Badges - "Delegate", "Secretary", "Guest" for 25th Convention (Boston, Mass) of the ILGWU. "Committee" of the 23rd Convention (Atlantic City), "Delegate" of the 63rd Convention, New Jersey, State Federation of Labor, Atlantic City, New Jersey1940"
- ILGWU - buttons & political buttons, Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Buttons - "Bill Clinton for President, ILGWU"; "McGovern"; "Humphrey/Muskie"; "Roosevelt, ILGWU"; "Register Vote Nov. 2"; "Harriman"; "Carter/Mondale, ILGWU"; "We Want "CHICK""
- ILGWU - badges, 1947; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Badges with bronze pendants - "Guest", "Delegate", "Sergeant. At Arms" for 26th Convention, Cleveland, 1947, "International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union"
- ILGWU - badges, 1937-1940; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Badges - "Guest" for 23rd Convention, Atlantic City, 1937"; "Delegate", "Staff", "Guest" for 40th Anniversary Convention, New York" (pendants shaped like thread spools)
- AFL-CIO - badges, 1955-1963; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Badges - "Guest" for 1st Convention, New York City1955"; 2nd, 3rd, 5th Biennial Conventions, "Guest" & "Delegate", badges are gold and silver in color with an "AFL-CIO" pendant hanging from the bottom. Each badge has a raised picture of the city in which the convention was held.
- AFL-CIO - badges, 1965-1985; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Badges - "Guest" & "Delegate" for the 6th Biennial Convention1965" (San Francisco, Calif); "Delegate" for the 7th1967" (Bal Harbour, Fla); "Delegate" for the 13th & 16th1979 & 1985" (Washington, DC, Anaheim, Calif). Badges are gold and silver in color
- AFL-CIO & ILGWU - badges, 1932-1963; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Badges - AFL-CIO - "Vice President" 3rd, 4th, 5thConstitutional Convention, Washington; "Guest" & "Gen. Sec. Treas. For 21 Convention; ILGWU - "Delegate" for 23 Convention; 28th Convention; "Exec.-Sec'y" for 23rd Convention.
- Badges and ribbons, miscellaneous organizations, 1914-1970; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Badges - "Vice President, G.E.B., Bienvenu a Montreal Welcome. International Ladies'1937"; "Delegate, The National Grange, 104th Annual Session1970 (New York State, AFL-CIO); "New York Cloak Joint Board1945"; "Honored Guest, 25th Biennial Convention - Atlantic City...1966"; "Joint Board Cloak & Skirt Makers..."
- Miscellaneous pendants, pins & badges., 1918-1985; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Ribbon - "Labor's Non-Partisan League of New Jersey"; pendants for ILGWU, AFL-CIO; badge for AFL-CIO; pins - ILGWU; assorted gold & bronze in color
- Miscellaneous pins, push pins, money clip, tie tack, key chain, Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 24)
  pins from ILGWU, AFL-CIO, GTB, LID, SindicatoTextil, N.U.T.G.W., K. of C.; tie tacks not labelled, money clip from ILGWU
- Miscellaneous memorabilia, 1964-1995; Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 25)
  2 badges from "Miami Beach, Florida, June 1995", name badges with red/white/blue "Delegate" ribbons attached to pendant - "ILGWU, 42nd Convention "; paper ribbon, red/white/blue - "Fight for the living, Pray for the dead"; gold medal commemorating the "First Union Health Center"
- ILGWU - scrapbook articles in mostly Yiddish, a few English, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Articles about ILGWU in English, but, majority are Yiddish.
- ILGWU - notes on strikes that took place, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Notes taken about individual strikes that took place within branches of the ILGWU
- Leon Stein, library request sheets, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Copies of request sheets from Leon Stein for books and articles at the New York Public Library
- Justice articles laminated to plaques, 1964; Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Two wooden plaques with issues of "Justice" laminated to the front. Issues, from Jan. 15 & April 1, 1964 (vol. XLVI, no.2 & XLVI, no.7)
- Plaques, one with a Justice article, and on from the United Jewish Appeal, 1964; Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Two wooden plaques one with an issue of Justice from April 15, 1964 (vol. XLVI, no. 8) and one is a Founder's Certificate from the United Jewish Appeal.
- Photograph of an Union label, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Black and white photograph of an Union label with lettering - "Int. Ladies Garment Workers Union, Union Made, ILGWU, AFL-CIO"; "Made in the U.S.A."
- Pot holders, ILGWU, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Two pot holders made from material with the ILGWU label as part of the design.
- Buttons & material chalk, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Buttons of different shapes and designs, used in garment factories, and chalk/crayons used to mark the material for sewing/cutting.
- Satin scarf - ILGWU, 1953; Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Satin scarf, green, white, orange from the twenty- eighth convention of the ILGWU, May 1953 in Chicago.
- Satin scarf - ILGWU, 1950; Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Satin scarf, blue, yellow, white from the 'Golden Jubilee' of the ILGWU, 1900-1950.
- ILGWU t-shirt, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 11)
  White t-shirt with the ILGWU union label on the front, owned by Eva Rosenberg and donated by Bernice E. Kalaminsky.
- ILGWU - cloth, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Small amount of cloth with the ILGWU union label on it. Red, blue, green, yellow, flowered, polka dot, and checkered design.
- Bound arbitration hearing between American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers' Assoc. & ILGWU, 1926; Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Bound book with details of the arbitration hearing between American Cloak and Suit and ILGWU
- ILGWU - Apron, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Apron made from material for the ILGWU with the union label on it. Material is Red, blue, green, yellow, flowered, polka dot, and checkered in design.
- ILGWU - button up shirt, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Button up shirt made from material for the ILGWU with the union label on it. Material is Red, blue, green, yellow, flowered, polka dot, and checkered in design.
- ILGWU - miscellaneous memorabilia, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Paper hats - "Roll Back Imports" & "Save Garment Jobs" each with the ILGWU label on it. Blue cloth hat with the ILGWU label affixed to it.Two ILGWU sewing kits. Two ball point pens & a pencil advertising the ILGWU. Cloth union label, w/ILGWU symbol on it. Pin, sticker and magnet, memo book and sponge all advertising ILGWU. "Honorary Life Membership" card.
- Union Health Center, watch, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Gold plated watch with black band, writing on face "First Union Health Center, ILGWU"
- ILGWU - miscellaneous buttons and pendants, memorabilia, 1965; Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Buttons - one is a picture of three men (Louis Hyman, Bourockovitch, ?), one "ILGWU, AFL-CIO, Organized 1900". Pendants from medals, and a tool that appears to have been used in a textile factory to cut threads.
- ILGWU - miscellaneous memorabilia, 1912-1947; Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Two ribbons - "Cloak & Skirt Makers Union I.L.G.W.U., New York, Labor Day, 1912", "Skirt & Cloth Dressmakers Union L. 23". Pendant from 26th Convention (Cleveland, 1947) and sticker advertising ILGWU in Spanish.
- ILGWU, shopping bags, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Plastic shopping bag with handle, red/white/blue, with lettering "ILGWU" all over it, and "Look for the Union Label" on the front, along with the ILGWU label.
- ILGWU - Constitution and receipt book in Yiddish, 1914; Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Small bound book, Constitution and receipt book of Abraham Barroff (in Yiddish)
- ILGWU - Funeral badge, 1911; Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Badge - "Ex. Board", "Cloak Tailors Union, Local 9, We Mourn Our Loss, April 5, 1911" -- Black ribbon on gold badge with tarnished tassels. The Funeral Badge is kept in the Kheel Center safe. If you would like to see it, please ask to speak with the Director of the Kheel Center.
- Miscellaneous buttons, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 23)
  "No NAFTA"; "Failure is Not and Option, New York State AFL-CIO"; "Fight for the living!, Workers Memorial Day - April 28"; "No SCABS"; "New York State AFL-CIO, I Love NY Products"; "New York Workers Working Together, Dinkins, For a Better New York"
- ILGWU key chain and button, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Key chain (6 the same) - "ILGWU, Union Made, Local 23-25"; button - "The Union for me I.L.G.W.U."
- ILGWU - misc. buttons, pins, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 25)
  pins - "Local 55, U.D.C., ILGWU"; "24th Convention, ILGWU, 1940, New York"; buttons - "No NAFTA, AFL-CIO"; "SIAMO UNO NEL '91"; "ILGWU, Made in U.S.A."; "UNIDOS en 1994"; "Support the Copper Strikers"; "Union Contract"; "On the move, ILGWU, Fortieth Convention, Hollywood, Florida, June 1989"
- ILWGU - misc. buttons, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 26)
  "I Support the Rank & File of Local 155, ILGWU"; "ILGWU for Mayor Dinkins '93"; "Local 155 I'm Registered to Vote"; "Contract '88"; "Local 155, ILGWU"; "We are ONE in '91"; "ILGWU for Dinkins"
- ILGWU, vented caps [loose in box], Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Vented caps (hats), blue & white with lettering "ILGWU" and the ILGWU label, made in the U.S.A.
- ILGWU - neck ties [loose in box], Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Gray, maroon, and blue neck ties, "Look For the Union Label"
- AFL-CIO plastic cup [loose in box], Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 29)
  White cup with lettering "Union Privilege, AFL-CIO
- Wooden desk note pad, engraved for David Dubinsky, Memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Wooden desk note pad holder, with a gold name plate on the top "To David Dubinsky From A.M.C. and B.W. of N.A.
- Paper weight from the National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1963; Memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Paper weight, two sided - side one -- picture of a globe with lettering "National Conference Brotherhood of Christians and Jews"; side two -- "Mass Media Award to International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union1963"
- Sealmaker for the Apparel Job Training and Research Corp., 1978; Memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Silver hand held Sealmaker - the seal has wording "Apparel Job Training and Research Corporation, Corporate Seal, 1978, New York"
- Sealmaker for the Italian Suit & Skirt Makers Union of New York, Memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Black Sealmaker--seal wording is "Italian Cloak & Skirt Makers Union of New York, Local No. 48, International Ladies Garment Workers Union, A.F. of L."
- Ceramic bust of David Dubinsky, 1952; Memorabilia (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Ceramic bust by Arturo Sofo, left side David Dubinsky's face.
- Satin banner 'Golden Jubilee' of the ILGWU, 1900-1950., Memorabilia (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Satin banner, blue, yellow, white from the 'Golden Jubilee' of the ILGWU, 1900-1950. [Large version of the scarf in box 2, folder 10]
- Knives, Memorabilia (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Two sharp knives shaped like machete, used for cutting cloth in factories.
- Knife, Memorabilia (Box 7, Folder 1)
  One sharp knife shaped like a machete, used for cutting cloth in factories.
- ILGWU banner, Banners; Memorabilia (Box 9.2, Folder 1)
  White nylon banner with the ILGWU Union Label printed on the front.
- ILGWU banner, Banners; Memorabilia (Box 9.3, Folder 1)
  White nylon banner with navy lettering "Union Yes, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union-AFL-CIO"
- ILGWU badges (dupls.), Memorabilia (Box 10, Folder 1)
- ILGWU badges (dupls.), Memorabilia (Box 11, Folder 1)
- ILGWU badges (dupls.), Memorabilia (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Official dues cards, 1972-1977; Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Yearly dues cards, held by Lois Hartel. -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - Miscellaneous labels, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Cloth, paper "Union Labels", some used in factories to be sewn into clothing, others used as patches. Some paper stickers with the 'Union Label' on them. -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - paper hats and sweat band, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 3)
  Paper and cloth hats from "ILGWU" conventions -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - souvenirs, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 4)
  Souvenirs - plastic rulers, letter openers and other misc. items -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - souvenirs, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 5)
  Souvenirs - plastic ice scraper, rubber sponges with lettering about the ILGWU on them. -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - campaign flyers, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 6)
  Campaign flyers and mailers sent out for Clinton Presidential campaign. -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - booklets, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Consumer booklets put out by ILGWU -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - Miscellaneous souvenirs, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 8)
  Sewing kits, rulers, 'shopping list' cards, etc., all with ILGWU info on them. -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - Miscellaneous souvenirs, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 9)
  Sewing kits, rain hats, note pads, etc. -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - Tie, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 10)
  Navy blue tie with the union label stitched onto it. -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - Miscellaneous souvenirs, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 11)
  Gold lighter, watch with union label as the face of the watch, jack knife -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - buttons, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 12)
  "Boycott Volunteer, ILGWU"; "United in 1994" [Eng., fre., spa.]; "Clinton/Gore, It's Time for Change!" [union label]; "Save Our Jobs, VETO the VETO, ILGWU"; "Roll back IMPORTS" -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - buttons, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 13)
  "Jane Wyman was right"; "Clinton/Gore"; two with union label on front; "Liberty & Union, ILGWU" [with Statue of Liberty face]; "ILGWU Price Watch Monitor"; "I was there to roll back imports, April 10, 1985, Harrisburg, PA"; "UNITI nel 1994" -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - buttons, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 14)
  "SIAMO, UNO, Nel '91"; "The Union for me I.L.G.W.U."; "Contract '88"; "ILGWU is family, American Family Celebration, Working for Change, May 14, 1988"; others are duplicates. -- All items in box 13 were part of a donation of items by Lois Hartel, items were split and put into appropriate collections.
- ILGWU - buttons, Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 15)